Ciaran Carson papers, circa 1970-2010
Emory University
- Printed material, 1975-2008, Series 4; Boxes 32 - 40, 61-62; OP 6 - 26
  - Other printed material, 1976-2006, Subseries 4.3; Boxes 39-40, 62; OP 21 - 26
    - Dog, with letter of solicitation, 30 June 1994 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - A Half-Door Near Cluny by Paul Muldoon, autographed Christmas card, 1997 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - A Hedge a Way: The Other Side of Emily Dickinson's Amherst by Daniel Lombardo, 22 August 2000 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - The Homestead Review, spring/summer 2001, with solicitation for contribution (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Irish Times-Aer Lingus Prize 1990 broadsides [shortlist broadside; "Gallery Press Applauds Ciaran Carson"] (Box OP21, Folder -)
    - "John Campbell: A Way with a Story of Times Past in Ireland," by Sheila Miller in The Guardian, 11 October 2006 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - "'The Luck of the Prize': V.S. Naipaul, First Winner of the David Cohen British Literature Prize" by Alastair Niven, no date (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - "Night in Jastarnia," poem by Cathal McCabe, 20 December 2000 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Paddy's Pig: Irony and Self-Irony in Irish Culture," by Lawrence J. Taylor (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Philip Ward Catalog (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Poetry Book Society materials and information (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Poetry International programs (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Poetry Ireland News, March/April 2002 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Poetry Ireland Review, winter 2001 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Poetry London, spring 2002 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Poetry Review, spring 2001 [special Irish poetry issue] (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Poetry Review, autumn 2001 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Program for City of Belfast Award Ceremony conferring the Freedom of the City on John Hewitt, 26 May 1983 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Reviews of other poets [Gallagher, Heaney, Mahon, O'Donoghue] (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of other poets [Ormsby's Rage for Order (review highlights Carson)] (Box OP22, Folder -)
    - Rhyming Dictionary, Carson's personal copy; includes note: "This is so well-worn, I decided to buy another, even if I don't know if I'll ever rhyme again" [2002] (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "A Runagate Tongue, or, English as We Speak It in Ulster," by John Wilson Foster, in Irish Literary Supplement, Fall 1993, p. 24; includes ALS from Foster 14 September 1993 (Box OP24, Folder -)
    - Schenkel, Elmar, various writings including interview and essays on Montague and poetry and place (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Seamus Heaney: An Interview," by Rand Brandes, Salmagundi, No. 80, Fall 1988 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "The Seed-Cutters" by Seamus Heaney, The Irish Press (?), no date (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Slam, Spam and Snakes," by Kevin Le Gendre in Independent on Sunday [about Don Patterson] (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "The Thief of Words," by Thomas Rain Crowe, with TLS from Crowe, 14 November 2000 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Wallflowers: A Lecture on Poetry, by Michael Donaghy (1999) (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "What You were not Looking for," baccalaureate address by Tess Gallagher, 25 May 1997 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - "The Wild Colonial Boy," photocopy of song (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "The Wild West Belfast Boy," by Brian Mullen, on the occasion of Carson's retirement from the Arts Council, 10 October 1998 (Box OP23, Folder -)
    - Miscellaneous printed material with literary subjects [1 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous printed material with literary subjects [2 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous printed material with literary subjects (Box OP24, Folder -)
    - Printed Material with Other Subjects
    - "Fiddlin' John Carson," article on Irish traditional music by Mark Wilson [circa 1976] (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "An Irishman Before the Mexican Inquisition, 1574-5," by P. E. H. Hair, in Irish Historical Studies, March 1971 (Box OP24)
    - Miscellaneous printed material about music (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous printed material about music (Box OP25, Folder -)
    - Miscellaneous printed material about visual arts (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous printed material with no specific subjects (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous printed material with no specific subjects (Box OP26, Folder -)
- Belfast Group worksheets, [1971-1972], Series 5; Box 41
  This series contains worksheets for the Belfast Group from 1971-1972. The Belfast Group, an informal writers' group where the participants read and discussed each other's work, was founded by the poet Philip Hobsbaum in 1963. Hobsbaum stopped his direction of the meetings when he moved back to England in 1966, but Seamus Heaney continued to organize the meetings off and on for the next six years. Early participants included Heaney, Longely, Mahon, James Simmons, and Stewart Parker. Paul Muldoon and Ciaran Carson joined the group in the early 1970s. Typically, one writer's work highlighted a given session. A small selection of poems or, less commonly, a short story would be mimeographed and distributed to participants. These "group sheets" organized by author document the development of both individual writers and a community of writers in Northern Ireland. The Group under Heaney's auspices finally ceased altogether in 1972 at a time of escalating political violence in Northern Ireland. More information about the Belfast Group may be found at http://chaucer.library.emory.edu/irishpoet/index.html.
  The Carson papers contain worksheets for the final year of the Belfast Group's existence, 1971-1972. In Carson's papers, these worksheets were gathered together in a folder with various cut-outs of published Carson and Heaney poems (See Subseries 4.1 and 4.3), as well as typescripts of poems found in The Insular Celts and Uncollected Poems. See these poems in Subseries 2.2.
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Carson, Ciaran: "Letter from Alaska," "Aranmore Island" (with three sections entitled "Erratics," "The Fault," and "American Wake"), "The Island Revisted," "Wheel," "Post Mortem on a Mass Grave," "The Clockwork Pigeon;" [undated] (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "Servant Boy," "The Last Mummer," "Gifts of Rain," "The Tollund Man," "Westering;" [8 November 1971] (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Longley, Michael: "Altera Cithera," "Three Posthumous Pieces," "The Island," "Casualty," "Badger," "Hedgehog," "Kingfisher," "Robin," "The Adulterer;" [31 January 1972] (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - MacLaverty, Bernard: "The Deep End;" [14 February 1972] (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - McMahon, Trevor: "Moth," "Worm," "The Planter Speaks," "Old Man," "To Those Involved in Rigid Disciplines," "Rat Song," "The Fool's Soliloquy," "Poem as Mammoth;" [22 November 1971] (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Muldoon, Paul: "Blowing Eggs," "The Radio Horse," "The Field Hospital," "On a Dog of Unlike Eyes," "The Lost Tribe," "The Upriver Incident," "Party Piece;" [25 October 1971] (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Photographs, 1977-2007, Series 6; Box 41-42
  This series contains photographs from 1977-2007. Photographs of Carson are mostly during the 1990s, though a number of undated photographs may be from earlier. Many of the photographs are of Carson at readings or formal events. Wherever possible, major literary figures in the photographs have also been identified.
  Groups of photographs are alphabetically arranged by principle subject, with individual photographs ordered chronologically when possible.
  - 1 (Box 42)
  - Ciaran Carson playing flute at Aspects: A Celebration of Irish Writing, Bangor, Co. Down, September 1994 [See also Series 1: Correspondence, 9 September 1995] (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Ciaran Carson with Paul Muldoon, included with ALS from Muldoon 28 January 1995 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Ciaran Carson with Edwin (?), November 1995 [See also subseries 4.3: Clair McNamee, "Writers' Portraits 1995 Catalogue"] (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Ciaran Carson in Wellington, New Zealand, 16 March 1996 [See also Series 1: Correspondence 12 April 1996] (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Ciaran Carson, snapshots from "Finnegans Awake Conference," May 2000 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Ciaran Carson with Michael Longley and other poets, circa June 2000, included with TLS from John Brown circa June 2000 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Ciaran Carson in Ashville, North Carolina, 18 March 2001 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Ciaran Carson with Ronald Schuchard and others, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Ciaran Carson in Jacksonville, Florida, 2003 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Ciaran Carson in Walberburg, 2005 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Ciaran Carson in Verona, Italy, 2006 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Ciaran Carson with Michael E. Scott and two unidentified men at Queen's University Belfast, 2007 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Ciaran Carson, [undated] (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] at ASU, [book jacket image] (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Ciaran Carson, [undated] contact sheet of head-shots (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] at Candide Jones's house in Winston Salem, North Carolina, color copies (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] with Dermot McLaughlin, Aly Bain, and unknown woman in Barcelona, Spain (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] with Dermot McLaughlin and Dessie Wilkinson in Barcelona, Spain (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] at home (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] with Medbh McGuckian, among others at reading (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] with Paul Muldoon, Dillon Johnston, Guinn Batten, snapshots probably near Wake Forest University (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] photos by Marcas O'Murchú [See also Series 1: undated correspondence: ALS from O'Murchú] (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] in Poland (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] portraits (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] portraits on compact disc (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Ciaran Carson [undated] with Seamus Heaney and others (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Statue of Dante at the Uffizi [undated] (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Tess Gallagher, signed photograph from March 1977 [included in Belfast Confetti notebook] (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Tess Gallagher with Carson's daughter, plus TLS from Gallagher, July 19, 1995 [manuscript notes for The Star Factory on envelope] (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified photograph of building [undated] (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - Unidentified photo of staged medieval battle, circa 1941 (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of unidentified persons (Box 42, Folder 33)
- Personal materials, 1975-2003, Series 7; Box 43; OP 27
  This series contains personal materials collected by Carson from 1975-2003. Materials include awards and honors, financial records, a passport, children's artwork, and other items.
  - Awards and Honors
  - Irish Book Awards, 1988 [awarded to The Irish for No] (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Irish Times-Aer Lingus, Irish Literature Prizes, 1992 [assorted materials for Carson as judge] (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - T.S. Eliot Prize, given by The Poetry Book Society for the year's best collection of new poetry, 1993 [awarded to First Language][includes promotional materials, congratulatory correspondence, press announcements] (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - T.S. Eliot Prize, 1996 [short-list honors for Opera Et Cetera] (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Ireland -Friends Provident Poetry Competition, 1996 [assorted materials for Carson as judge including poetry selections] (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Belfast Arts Awards for Best Literature Project, 1997 [awarded to Opera Et Cetera] (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Yorkshire Post Book of the Year Award, confirmation letter, May 7, 1998 [awarded to The Star Factory] (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Irish American Cultural Institute (IACI) Poetry Award, 2000 [includes TLS award announcement and fax from CC to IACI with biographical data] (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - David Cohen British Literature Prize, 2002 [correspondence and reading list for Carson as judge] (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - The Oxford Weidenfeld Translation Prize, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - The Society of Authors' Prizes, the Cholmondeley Awards to Recognise the Achievement of Individual Poets, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - The Glen Dimplex New Writers Awards, no date [Carson as judge] (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Other
  - Belfast information (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Bills and finances (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Children's artwork (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Diploma, Queens University (Box OP27, Folder -)
  - Family miscellany (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Notes, addresses, agendas [assorted] (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Passport (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Sketch of Medbh McGuckian [July 1, 1975] (Box 43, Folder 19)
- Subject files, Series 8; Box 44
  This series contains files that include correspondence, printed material, and unpublished documents collected by Carson on various subjects. Files concern the Seamus Heaney Centre, which was directed by Carson, the Back Door project on Irish poets, and other topics of interest to Carson.
  - American Conference for Irish Studies, 8 July 2004 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The Back Door, correspondence regarding proposed project to co-edit a special edition on younger Irish poets [summer 1977] [See also Subseries 3.1: The Back Door, including submissions by various Irish poets including Heaney, Longley, Muldoon, and Boland] (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Irish Traditional Music Archive (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Seamus Heaney Centre, Queen's University, no date (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Spiritualism, 1999-2002 (Box 44, Folder 5)
- Arts Council of Northern Ireland records, 1973-1998, Series 9; Boxes 45-47
  This series contains material related to the Arts Council of Northern Ireland from 1973-1985. Materials include grant applications, correspondence, project files, and photographs. Ciaran Carson worked as Traditional Arts Officer for the Arts Council of Northern Ireland (ACNI) from 1976-1998. During his time as Traditional Arts Officer, Carson published his first prose work that examined Irish Traditional Music, an Appletree Press guide book called Irish Traditional Music (1986). He recommenced his public life as a poet with the 1987 publication of The Irish for No, but his interest in and work on behalf of traditional music continued, culminating in his intimate and celebrated consideration of Irish music entitled Last Night's Fun: About Time, Food and Music (1996). Carson resigned from the ACNI in October 1998.
  While these Arts Council materials are arranged in four subsections, the folders themselves retain Carson's own system of organization. Thus, in most cases the names of particular folders were originally Carson's. "General Materials" contains documents largely pertaining to financial and other such administrative records. "Projects" contains mostly correspondence between the Arts Council and various groups and individuals involved in the organization of specific cultural events and programs. "Correspondence" collects more general bodies of communication between the Arts Council and those it supports, whether individuals or institutions. The final subsection, "Printed and Other Material" gathers miscellaneous materials such as photos and negatives as well as press clippings.
  - General Materials
  - Applications for Grant Aid, 1978-1981 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Applications for Grant Aid, 1982-1983 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Applications for Grant Aid, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Applications for Grant Aid by Carson, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - District Councils, 1973-1978 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Entertainment Returns, 1981-1982 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Job Description of Traditional Arts Officer, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Subsidies for Performers, 1976-1984 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - The Poet's Chair, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Projects
  - Armagh Pipers' Club, January 1980 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Audio Arts, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Collecting Audio and Video, 1976-1978 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Collecting Songs and Music, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Community Arts, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Crafts, 1978-1980 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Dancing, 1976-1979 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Dancing: Andersontown Ceili Club (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Festivals of Traditional Singing, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Folk Music Projects, 1980-1981 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Music Classes, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Music Classes and Educational Agencies, 1976-1979 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Music Classes [Other Bodies], 1980 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Other Recordings, 1973-1985 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Radio and Television [Countdown to the Festival], 1976-1977 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Seminars and Feiseanna, 1976-1979 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Seminars and Feiseanna, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Slow Air, 1975-1978 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Traditional Music Festivals, 1979-1984 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - You and Yours: Traditional Music Tour, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Young Arts, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence
  - Appletree Press, 1976-78 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Appletree Press, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Blackstaff Press, 1973-1979 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Blackstaff Press, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, 1975-1980 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Comhdháil Náisíunta Na Gaeilge, 1976-1977 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Other Artists, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Culman Cholmcille, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Ministry of Education, 1970-1976 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Musicians' Correspondence, 1977-1982 [photos, 45 rpm singles, clippings] (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Other Clubs and Societies, 1975-1985 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Other Presses, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Other Promotions, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Siamsa Tire [The National Folk Theatre of Ireland], 1978-1979 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Ulster Federation of Folk Clubs and Other Such Bodies, 1980-1981 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Printed and Other Materials
  - Photos, negatives of July 12 arches (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Press Comment and Reviews, 1973-1978 [includes James Simmons review] (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Tyrone Guthrie Center, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 15)
Index of Selected Correspondents
This index, which relates to the correspondence in Series 1, covers letters from 1973-1999.
Batten, Guinn 1995 July 29, ALS, 1p. undated APCS [August 7] 1996 September 23, TLS, 1p. 1999 May 22, TLS, 2pp. CC to GB: 1999 June 1, TLS, pp. 2 1999 August 4, TLS, 3pp.
Belton, Neil 1993 August 17, TLS, 1p. 1993 August 27, TLS, 1p. 1993 November 3, TLS, 1p. 1993 December 9, TLS, 1p. CC to NB: 1994 January 11, TLS, 1p. 1994 January [?], TLS, 1p. 1994 February 4, APCS, 1p. CC to NB: 1994 May [?], TLS, 1p. 1994 October 13, TLS, 1p. 1994 November 30, TLS, 1p. 1995 July 7, TLS, 2pp. 1995 October, TLS, 2pp. CC to NB: October 17, TLS 1p. 1995 October 19, TLS, 1p. 1996 January 22, TLS, 1p. CC to NB: 1996 January 30, TLS, 1p. 1996 February 1, TLS, 1p. 1997 March 20, TLS 2pp. 1997 March 24, APCS CC to NB: 1997 March 25, TLS, 1p. CC to NB: 1997 June 26, TLS, 3pp. 1997 July 31, ALS, 1p. 1998 April 28, TLS, 1p. 1998 June 1, TLS, 2pp. 1998 June 15, TLS, 2pp. CC to NB: 1998 June [?], TLS, 1p. 1998 August 4, TLS, 1p. CC to NB: 1998 August 6, TLS, 1p. CC to NB: 1998 August 7, TLS, 1p. 1998 October 12, TLS, 1p. 1999 May 13, TLS, 2pp. 1999 May 17 TLS, 1p. CC to NB: 1999 June 3, TLS, 3pp. 1999 August 10, TLS, 1p. CC to NB: 1999 August, 1p. 1999 August 12, TLS, 1p.
Brandes, Rand 1989 October 10, APCS 1992 October 5, TLS, 1p. 1994 January [?], APCS 1994 February 7, TLS, 1p. CC to RB: 1994 Februrary 9, TLS, 1p. 1994 March 1994 July 22, ALS, 1p. CC to RB: 1995 February 22, fax, 2pp.
Byatt, Antonia S. 1994 June 22, TLS, 1p. 1994 October 27, TLS, 2pp. 1996 November 27, TLS, 1p. 1997 January 21, TLS 1p. 1997 May 1, TLS, 1p.
Coady, Michael 1998 August 9, ALS, 1p.
Dorgan, Theo 1993 September 2, TLS, 1p. 1994 September 19, APCS 1999 July 9, TLS, 2pp.
Drabble, Margaret 1998 October 16, TLS, 1p. CC to MD: 1998 October 21, TLS, 1p. 1999 January 29, TLS, 1p.
Dunne, Seán 1992 December 15, TLS, 1p.
Durcan, Paul 1990 October 2, APCS
Fallon, Peter 1977 July 24, ALS, 1p. 1988 January 28, TLS to Neil Astley at Bloodaxe Books 1988 May 6, TLS, 1p. [incomplete] 1989 April 14, ALS, 1p. 1990 spring [undated] note with responses to Belfast Confetti 1990 July 6, TLS, 4pp. 1990 July 6, TLS, 1p. 1990 July 8, ALS, 3pp. 1990 September 12, 2pp. 1991 April 22, ALS, 1p. 1993 March 23, ALS, 1p. CC to PF 1993 August 5, TLS with First Language blurb 1993 August 31, faxed ALS, 3pp. [re: blurb] CC to PF 1993 September 10, ALS (copy), 1p. 1993 September 28, APCS, 2pp. 1993 November 7, ALS, 2pp. 1993 November 12, ALS, 2pp. CC to PF: 1994 March 9, ALS, 1p. CC to PF: 1994 April 27, ALS, 1p. 1994 September 14, ALS, 1p., with First Language awards materials 1994 December 2, ALS, 1p. 1995 January 19, ALS, 2pp. 1995 April 18, ALS, 1p. 1995 July 5, ALS, 1p. CC to PF: 1996 January 17, TLS, 1p. CC to PF: 1996 February 16, TLS, 1p. with blurb for Opera Et Cetera 1996 May 15, ALS, 1p. 1997 October 24, TLS, 1p. [See Subseries 2.2: The Alexandrine Plan, corrected typescript] 1998 January 6, ALS, 2pp. 1998 January 27, ALS, 1p. 1998 February 6, TLS, 1p. CC to PF: 1998 March 13, TLS, 1p. 1998 March 19, ALS, 4pp. 1998 March 23, ALS, 1p. 1998 May 12, ALS, 1p. 1998 July 22, ALS, 1p. 1998 September 18, ALS, 3pp. CC to PF: 1998 September 23, TLS, 1p. 1999 April 15, ALS, 2pp. 1999 July 2, TLS, 1p. 1999 July 19, ALS, 3pp. CC to PF: 1999 July 26, TLS, 2pp. 1999 April 26, ALS, 2pp. undated: ALS, 1p.
Flannagan, Tom 1990 fall [undated], TLS, 2pp.
Gallagher, Tess 1970's, APCS 1989 March 3, ALS, 2pp. plus photocopies of poems 1990 January 12, ALS, 2pp. 1990 April 2, APCS, 2pp. 1994 February 22, TLS, 1p. 1994 May 23, APCS, 2pp. 1994 October 17, TLS, 1p. 1994 [undated], APCS 1995 May 17, TLS, 4pp. [itinerary] 1995 June 5, APCS, 2pp. 1995 July 26, ALS, 2pp. 1995 September 7, ALS, 4pp. 1995 October 17, TLS, 2pp. CC to TG 1995 October 25, TLS, 1p. 1995 December, 11, TLS 2pp. 1996 March 20, TLS, 3pp. 1997 June 11, TLS, 2pp. 1997 June 13, TLS, 3pp. 1997 June 16, TLS, 3pp. 1997 June 20, TLS, 2pp. 1997 June 22, TLS, 4pp. CC to TG: 1997 June 30, TLS, 2pp. CC to TG: 1997 July 8, TLS 1p. 1997 July 15, TLS, 2pp. 1997 September 8, TLS, 2pp. 1997 October-November [?], TLS, 1p. 1997 November [?], TLS, 2pp. 1997 December 30, ALS, 1p. 1998 January 30, TLS, 2pp. included with TS of The Twelfth of Never amended by TG [See Subseries 2.2: The Twelfth of Never] 1998 February 1, ALS, 2pp. included with TS of The Twelfth of Never amended by TG [See Subseries 2.2: The Twelfth of Never] 1998 April 5, ALS, 1p. included with TS of The Twelfth of Never amended by TG, and photos of paintings by Josie Gray 1998 April 8, ALS, 1p. CC to TG: 1998 April 22, TLS, 2pp. 1998 August 15, ALS, 2pp. 1998 November 6, ALS, 4pp. 1999 April 23, ALS, 2pp. CC to TG: 1999 November 1, TLS, 1p. 2000 March 13, ALS, 2pp.
Ginsburg, Allen 1993 February 5, ALS, 1p.
Groarke, Vona 1998 August 2, APCS
Hammond, David 1994 February 22, ALS, 1p. 1997 December 23, ALS, 1p.
Heaney, Seamus [RESTRICTED] 1973 November 1, 1p. 1996 April 6, TLS, 2pp. 1999 November 12, APCS 1999 November 17, APCS